I've seen over and over that
我多次看到(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，刘竞)
one of the most reliable ways to
一个最可靠的得到
get a high performance machine learning
一个高性能的机器学习
system is to take
系统的方法是
a low bias learning algorithm
采取一个低偏差的机器学习算法
and to train it on a massive training set.
并且在用大量的数据集去训练它。
But where did you get so much training data from?
但是你该从哪里去获得这么多的训练数据呢？
Turns out that the machine earnings
机器收益证明了
there's a fascinating idea called artificial
有一个非常吸引人的思想叫做
data synthesis, this doesn't
人工数据合成，这种思想并不
apply to every single problem, and
适用于每个单独的问题，当把它
to apply to a specific
运用于一个具体的特定
problem, often takes some thought and innovation and insight.
问题时，需要经过一些思考，改进和洞察力。
But if this idea applies
但是假如这个思想应用在
to your machine, only problem, it
在你的机器上，唯一的问题是，
can sometimes be a an
有时，为你的学习算法
easy way to get a
获得一个巨大的
huge training set to give to your learning algorithm.
训练集将是很容易的。
The idea of artificial
人工数据合成
data synthesis comprises of two
包含两个
variations, main the first
变化形式，第一个最主要的
is if we are essentially creating
是我们是否有必要
data from [xx], creating new data from scratch.
从[xx]中去生成数据，也就是从头开始去创新数据。
And the second is if
第二种是我们
we already have it's small
是否已经有了算法的一小
label training set and we
部分标签训练集
somehow have amplify that training
并且以某种方式扩充了训练集
set or use a small training
或者是把一小部分训练集
set to turn that into
转换成了
a larger training set and in
一个较大的数据集
this video we'll go over both those ideas.
在这一个视频中，我们将仔细学习这两种思路。
To talk about the artificial data
在讲到人工数据
synthesis idea, let's use
合成思想时，让我们
the character portion of
借用一下成像光学字符识别
the photo OCR pipeline, we
管道中的字符部分，
want to take it's input image
我们想采用它的输入图像
and recognize what character it is.
去识别出它是什么字符。
If we go out and collect
假如我们出去收集到
a large label data set,
一个大的标签数据集，
here's what it is and what it look like.
也就是它是什么和它像什么。
For this particular example, I've chosen a square aspect ratio.
在这一个特殊的例子中，我选择了一个正方形的长宽比。
So we're taking square image patches.
所以我们采用正方形的图像块。
And the goal is to take
我们的目标是获得
an image patch and recognize the
一个图像块并且识别出
character in the middle of that image patch.
图像块中央的字符。
And for the sake of simplicity,
为了简单，
I'm going to treat these images
我打算把这些图像当做
as grey scale images, rather than color images.
灰度图像来处理，不是把它们当做彩色图像。
It turns out that using color
事实证明把它们当做彩色图像来处理
doesn't seem to help that much for this particular problem.
对于这个具体的问题而言看起来帮助不大。
So given this image patch, we'd
对于这个给定的图像块，
like to recognize that that's a
我们会把它识别为"T"。
T. Given this image patch,
对于这个图像块，
we'd like to recognize that it's an 'S'.
我们会把它识别为一个"S".
Given that image patch we
对于这个图像块，我们
would like to recognize that as an 'I' and so on.
会把它识别为一个“I”，等等。
So all of these, our
因此，对于所有
examples of row images, how
这些行图像的例子，
can we come up with a much larger training set?
我们该如何得到一个更大的训练集呢？
Modern computers often have a
现代计算机通常有一个
huge font library and
庞大的字体库，
if you use a word processing
并且假如你使用一个字处理
software, depending on what word
软件，主要看你使用的
processor you use, you might
是什么字处理软件，你可能
have all of these fonts and
有所有这些字体，
many, many more Already stored inside.
并且还有更多的已经存储在里面了。
And, in fact, if you go different websites, there
并且，事实上，假如你去不同的网站，
are, again, huge, free font
网上还有其它的大的，
libraries on the internet we
免费的字体库，从那里
can download many, many different
我们能下载许多许多不同
types of fonts, hundreds or perhaps thousands of different fonts.
类型的字体，几百甚至是几千种不同的字体。
So if you want more
所以，假如你想
training examples, one thing you
得到更多训练实例，一件
can do is just take
你可以做的事情正是
characters from different fonts
得到不同的字体的字符，
and paste these characters against
并且把这些字符粘贴到
different random backgrounds.
任意不同的背景下。
So you might take this ----  and paste that c against a random background.
所以，你可以得到这些字符C并且把它粘在任意的背景下。
If you do that you now have
假如你做了这些，那么你现在
a training example of an
就有了一个关于
image of the character C.
字符C的图像的训练样例。
So after some amount of
所以在完成一定数量的
work, you know this,
工作之后，你就会发现
and it is a little bit of
合成这些逼真的数据
work to synthisize realistic looking data.
只有很少的工作要做。
But after some amount of work,
在完成一定量的工作之后，
you can get a synthetic training set like that.
你可以得到像那样的合成的训练集。
Every image shown on the right was actually a synthesized image.
在右侧显示的图像实际上是一个合成的图像。
Where you take a font,
当你采用一个字体时，
maybe a random font downloaded off
可能是一个从网上下载的字体，
the web and you paste
你把基于这种字体的
an image of one character
一个字符的图像或者
or a few characters from that font
是几个字符的图像
against this other random background image.
粘贴到另一个任意的背景图像下。
And then apply maybe a little
可以应用一点
blurring operators  -----of app
模糊算子，比如
finder, distortions that app
应用程序取景器，失真，
finder, meaning just the sharing
应用程序取景器，意味着共享，
and scaling and little rotation
缩放和轻微的
operations and if you
旋转操作，假如你
do that you get a synthetic
做了这些，你得到一个
training set, on what the one shown here.
合成的训练集，就是这里显示的这个。
And this is work,
这种工作，
grade, it is, it takes
它也是有好有坏的，
thought at work, in order to
为了使合成的数据更逼真，
make the synthetic data look realistic,
在工作中是需要花费心思的，
and if you do a sloppy
如果在生成合成数据的工作中
job in terms of how
你没有认真去做，
you create the synthetic data then it actually won't work well.
那么所生成的合成数据实际上是不能有效工作的。
But if you look at
但是，假如你看到合成的
the synthetic data looks remarkably similar to the real data.
数据与真实数据非常相似，
And so by using synthetic data
那么使用合成的数据，
you have essentially an unlimited
你就必然能为
supply of training examples for
你的人工训练合成提供
artificial training synthesis And
无限的训练数据样例。
so, if you use this
因此，假如你使用
source synthetic data, you have
这个合成数据源，你就必然
essentially unlimited supply of
就可以利用这些无限的
label data to create
标签数据为字符识别
a improvised learning algorithm
问题生成一个
for the character recognition problem.
学习算法。
So this is an example of
所以这是一个
artificial data synthesis where youre
数据合成的例子，
basically creating new data from
你基本是从零开始
scratch, you just generating brand new images from scratch.
产生数据，也就是你从零开始产生新的图像。
The other main approach to artificial data
另一个主要的人工
synthesis is where you
数据合成方式是
take a examples that you
你使用一个当前
currently have, that we take
已经有的样例，也就是说
a real example, maybe from
我们有一个真实的样例，
real image, and you create
可能是一个真实的图像，
additional data, so as to
你产生附加的数据，
amplify your training set.
以扩充你的训练集。
So here is an image of a compared
这是一个真实图像
to a from a real image,
的对比图像,
not a synthesized image, and
不是一个合成的图像，
I have overlayed this with
我在上面覆盖了网格线
the grid lines just for the purpose of illustration.
只是为了说明问题。
Actually have these ----.
实际上有这许多。
So what you
所以你能做
can do is then take this
的是把字母放在
alphabet here, take this image
这里，向这图像中
and introduce artificial warpings[sp?]
引入一些人工的拉伸
or artificial distortions into the
或者是一些
image so they can
人工的失真，
take the image a and turn
经过这些操作，可以把
that into 16 new examples.
字母A变成这16个新的样例。
So in this way you can
所以采用这种办法，
take a small label training set
你可以得到一个小的标签训练集
and amplify your training set
并且你扩充你的训练集，
to suddenly get a lot
突然得到
more examples, all of it.
更多样例，所有的这些图像。
Again, in order to do
此外，在这一应用中
this for application, it does
所做的这些，
take thought and it does
需要花费心思，
take insight to figure out
需要洞察力去
what our reasonable sets of
判断出合理的失真
distortions, or whether these
操作集，或者是这些操作
are ways that amplify and multiply
是否是扩充和增加
your training set, and for
训练集的方法，
the specific example of
对于字符识别这一
character recognition, introducing these
具体的例子，引入这些
warping seems like a natural
拉伸看起来是一个
choice, but for a
很自然的选择，但是对于不同
different learning machine application, there may
机器学习应用来说，可能
be different the distortions that might make more sense.
另外一些不同的失真将会更合理。
Let me just show one example
让我给大家展示一个
from the totally different domain of speech recognition.
完全不同的语音识别领域的问题。
So the speech recognition, let's say
对于语音识别，假如说
you have audio clips and you
你有音频片段，
want to learn from the audio
你想从中
clip to recognize what were
识别出哪些单词出现在了
the words spoken in that clip.
语音片段中。
So let's see how one labeled training example.
因此，让我们来看看是如何给训练样例加标签的。
So let's say you have one
那么，让我们说假定你已经有了一个
labeled training example, of someone
加了标签的训练样例，就是
saying a few specific words.
某个人在说一些特定的单词。
So let's play that audio clip here.
因此，让我们播放一下这个语音片段。
0 -1-2-3-4-5.
0，1，2，3，4，5.
Alright, so someone
好吧，有人在
counting from 0 to 5,
从0数到5.
and so you want to
然后你想要应用
try to apply a learning algorithm
一个学习算法去试图
to try to recognize the words said in that.
识别出那个人说了哪些单词。
So, how can we amplify the data set?
那么，我们该如何扩充数据集呢？
Well, one thing we do is
很好，我们可以做的一件事情就是
introduce additional audio distortions into the data set.
引入附加的语音失真到数据集中。
So here I'm going to
所以，我将加入
add background sounds to simulate a bad cell phone connection.
加入一些背景声音去模拟一个较差的手机通话连接。
When you hear beeping sounds, that's
当你听到蜂鸣声，实现上
actually part of the audio
这是音频记录的一部分，
track, that's nothing wrong with the speakers, I'm going to play this now.
不是说话者的错误，现在我开始播放了。
0-1-2-3-4-5.
0，1，2，3，4，5.
Right, so you can listen
好了，你只可以听到
to that sort of audio clip and
那种音频片段， 并且
recognize the sounds,
识别出声音，
that seems like another useful training
这看起来像是另外一种
example to have, here's another example, noisy background.
值得拥有的训练样例。这是另外一种例子，吵杂的背景。
Zero, one, two, three
0，1，2，3
four five you know
4，5，在背景中还有
of cars driving past, people walking
行使的汽车经过，人在走路。
in the background, here's another
这是另外
one, so taking the original
一个，使用原来的干净的音频片段，
clean audio clip so
原来那个音频片段
taking the clean audio of
有人在说
someone saying 0 1 2 3
0,1,2,3
4 5 we can then automatically
4,5,然后，我们能自动
synthesize these additional training
合成这些附加的
examples and thus amplify
训练集，把单个的训练集
one training example into maybe four different training examples.
扩展到可能四种不同的训练样例。
So let me play this final
所以让我也播放一下最后
example, as well.
这个样例。
0-1 3-4-5 So by
0，1，3，4，5. 因此，通过
taking just one labelled example,
使用一个已经加了标签的样例，
we have to go through the effort
我们不得不通过努力
to collect just one labelled example
去以收集另一个带
fall of the 01205, and by
标签的样例01205，通过
synthesizing additional distortions,
合成附加的失真，
by introducing different background sounds,
通过引入不同的背景声音，
we've now multiplied this one
我们把一个样例扩充
example into many more examples.
成许多更多的样例。
Much work by just automatically
最的做多的工作就是自动
adding these different background sounds
添加许多不同的背景声音
to the clean audio Just
到干净的音频中。对于引入失真
one word of warning about synthesizing
去合成数据，
data by introducing distortions: if
只有一点要提醒的是
you try to do this
假如你尝试
yourself, the distortions you
自己去完成，你引入的失真
introduce should be representative the source
应该对于背景声音
of noises, or distortions, that
或者失真而言具有代表性，
you might see in the test set.
这一点你会在测试集中发现。
So, for the character recognition example,
所以，对于字符识别的例子，
you know, the working things
你知道，开始引入的
begin introduced are actually kind
可工作的事物实际上是
of reasonable, because an image
某种合理的事物，因为
A that looks like that, that's,
一个A的图像就是像那个样子，
could be an image that
也就是说，是一个我们实际上可以在
we could actually see in a test set.Reflect
一个测试集中看到的那样的图像。
a fact And, you know, that
回想一下这一事实。 你知道，
image on the upper-right, that
右上边的那个图像是一个
could be an image that we could imagine seeing.
在我们想象中能看到的图像。
And for audio, well, we do
对于音频而言，
wanna recognize speech, even against
我们想要识别出的讲话，
a bad self internal connection, against
即使是在一个差的在各种不同类型的
different types of background noise, and
背景噪音中的自我内部连接，
so for the audio, we're again
因此，对于音频，我们
synthesizing examples are actually
再次合成样例，它们能够
representative of the sorts of
代表不同类型的
examples that we want to
我们想要区分开的样例，
classify, that we want to recognize correctly.
而且我们也想要能够正确的识别。
In contrast, usually it does
相反，通常当你
not help perhaps you actually
把一个有意义的数据当作噪音
a meaning as noise to your data.
加入到你的数据中，对工作没有多大帮助。
I'm not sure you can see
我不确定你能明白这个，
this, but what we've done
但是我们这里已经做的
here is taken the image, and
就是拍摄了照片，
for each pixel, in each
并且对于4幅
of these 4 images, has just
图中的每一个像素，都加入
added some random Gaussian noise to each pixel.
一些随机的高斯噪音。
To each pixel, is the
对于每一个像素，
pixel brightness, it would
也就是像素亮度，
just add some, you know, maybe Gaussian random noise to each pixel.
加入一些可能是高斯随机噪音。
So it's just a totally meaningless noise, right?
所以，它只是一个完全没有意义的噪音，对吧？
And so, unless you're expecting
因此，除非你期望在你
to see these sorts of pixel
的测试集中看到这种
wise noise in your test
像素间的对比噪音，
set, this sort of
那么这种纯随机的无意义
purely random meaningless noise is less likely to be useful.
的噪音将很可能就是无用的。
But the process of artificial
但是这种人工
data synthesis it is you
数据合成的过程是你
know a little bit of
知道一点技巧，
an art as well and sometimes
并且有时候你
you just have to try it and see if it works.
仅仅是尝试一下，看它是否起作用。
But if you're trying to
但是当你在决定
decide what sorts of distortions
该添加哪种
to add, you know, do
失真时，
think about what other meaningful
考虑其他你
distortions you might add that
可能添加的有意义的失真，
will cause you to generate additional
可能会导致你生成一些附加
training examples that are at
训练样例，它们相对于你希望在
least somewhat representative of the
测试集中见到的图像而言，不具有
sorts of images you expect to see in your test sets.
代表性.
Finally, to wrap up this
最后，在完成这一视频时，
video, I just wanna say
我想说
a couple of words, more about
几句话，更多的是关于
this idea of getting loss
通过数据合成去解决
of data via artificial data synthesis.
数据亏损问题。
As always, before expending a lot
像以前一样，在作出
of effort, you know, figuring out
努力之前，应该想到
how to create artificial training
如何生成人工训练
examples, it's often a good
样例，这是一个很好的
practice is to make sure
做法，它可以确保
that you really have a low biased
你真正有一个非常低偏差的
crossfire, and having a
问题，有更多的
lot more training data will be of help.
训练数据将会更有帮助。
And standard way to do
一个标准物方法是
this is to plot the learning
绘制一个学习
curves, and make sure that
曲线，确定你只有
you only have a low
一个低偏差
as well, high variance falsifier.
同时也是高方差的伪造器。
Or if you don't have a low
或者如果你没有一个低
bias falsifier, you know,
偏差的伪造器，那么，
one other thing that's worth trying
另外一件值得尝试的事情
is to keep increasing the number
就是持续增加
of features that your classifier
你的分类器的特征数量，
has, increasing the number of
增加你的
hidden units in your network,
网络的隐藏单元的数量，
saying, until you actually have a
也就是说，直到你实际上有了
low bias falsifier, and only
一个低偏差的伪造器，
then, should you put
并且是直到那时，你才应该
the effort into creating a
花费力气去生成
large, artificial training set, so
大量的，人工的训练集，所以
what you really want to avoid
你真正想要避免的
is to, you know, spend
就是，花费一
a whole week or spend a few
整个星期或者是花费
months figuring out how
几个月去想该
to get a great artificially
如何去得到一个大的
synthesized data set.
人工合成的数据集。
Only to realize afterward, that,
只实现后面的工作，
you know, your learning algorithm, performance
你知道的，即使当你有大量的训练集，
doesn't improve that much, even when you're given a huge training set.
你的学习算法的性能也不可能改进太多。
So that's about my usual advice
所以，这也是我通常的
about of a testing that
关于测试的一个建议，
you really can make use
在你花费很大的力气去
of a large training set before
寻找大的训练集以前，
spending a lot of effort going out to get that large training set.
你可以真正利用这样一个大的训练集。
Second is, when i'm working
第二，就是当我
on machine learning problems, one question
在研究机器学习问题时，我经常问
I often ask the team
和我一起工作的小组，
I'm working with, often ask my
我也经常问我的学生
students, which is, how much work
的一个问题，就是获得我当前拥有的数据
would it be to get 10 times as much date as we currently had.
的10倍的数据将会花费多少工作。
When I face a new machine
当我面临一个新的
learning application very often I
机器学习应用时，通常
will sit down with a team
我会和整个小组一起坐下来，
and ask exactly this question,
仔细询问这个问题，
I've asked this question over and
我已经反复的问过这个问题，
over and over and I've
并且，我一直也很
been very surprised how often
惊讶问题的答案
this answer has been that.
通常都是那样。
You know, it's really not that hard,
你知道，它其实没有那么难，
maybe a few days of work
可能至多是
at most, to get ten times
几天的工作，就可以获得
as much data as we currently
10倍于当前
have for a machine
我们的机器
running application and very
运行应用的数据,并且
often if you can get
通常是假如你有当前
ten times as much data there
的十倍的数据，那么
will be a way to make your algorithm do much better.
将会有办法使你的算法工作得更好。
So, you know, if you
因此，假如
ever join the product team
你曾经参加了
working on some machine learning
过专门从事研发一些
application product this is
机器学习应用产品的小组，
a very good questions ask yourself
这是一个很好的你应该问自己、
ask the team don't be
问小组的问题，不要太惊讶
too surprised if after a
假如经过几分钟
few minutes of brainstorming if your
的讨论后，你的小组就想到
team comes up with a
了可以得到
way to get literally ten
毫不夸张的十倍于
times this much data, in
现在拥有的数据的办法，
which case, I think you would
在这种情况下，
be a hero to that team,
你将成为小组的英雄，
because with 10 times as
因为如果有了十倍多的数据，
much data, I think you'll really
并且从这么多的数据中学习，
get much better performance, just from learning from so much data.
我认为你的算法将会有更好的性能。
So there are several waysand
因此，有几个方法
that comprised both the ideas
可以包括利用
of generating data from
随机字体
scratch using random fonts and so on.
来从头产生数据等思想。
As well as the second idea
同样的，第二个思想
of taking an existing example and
是利用现有的例子，
and introducing distortions that amplify
引入一些失真
to enlarge the training set A
来增加、扩大训练集。
couple of other examples of
一些其它获得得更多
ways to get a lot more
数据的方法
data are to collect the
的例子就是就是收集数据
data or to label them yourself.
或者自己给他们加标签。
So one useful calculation that
因此一个我经常
I often do is, you know,
做的有用的计算就是
how many minutes, how many
获得一定数量
hours does it take to
的样例需要
get a certain number of
多少分钟、多少小时，
examples, so actually sit down and
所以实际上是
figure out, you know, suppose it
坐下来估计一下，假如
takes me ten seconds to
给一个样例加标签
label one example then
需要十分秒钟，然后，再假设
and, suppose that, for
在我们的应用中，
our application, currently we
我们当前
have 1000 labeled examples examples
有1000个标记过的样例。
so ten times as
所以得到
much of that would be
十倍数据的时间
if n were equal to ten thousand.
n就是一万秒。
A second way to
第二个获得
get a lot of data is
更多数据的办法就是
to just collect the data and you label it yourself.
收集数据，然后自己标记它。
So what I mean by this is
所以，我这么说的意思是
I will often set down and
我经常会坐下来
do a calculation to figure
并且计算出
out how much time, you
需要多少时间，
know just like how many hours
比如你应该知道
will it take, how many
这需要多少小时，也就是
hours or how many days will
你或者其它人
it take for me or
坐下来并且
for someone else to just sit
收集十倍于
down and collect ten times
当前所拥有的
as much data, as we have
数据，并给他们
currently, by collecting the data ourselves and labeling them ourselves.
加标签需要多少小时，多少天。
So, for example, that, for
例如，
our machine learning application, currently
我们的机器学习应用，当前
we have 1,000 examples, so M 1,000.
我们有1000个样例，所以M等于1000.
That what we do is sit
所以我们做的就是
down and ask, how long does
就下来，问一下，实际收集
it take me really to collect and label one example.
并给一个样例加标签需要多少时间。
And sometimes maybe it will
有时它可能会
take you, you know ten
花费你十秒
seconds to label
去给一个新样例
one new example, and so
加标签，因此，如果我需要
if I want 10 X as many examples, I'd do a calculation.
十倍多的样例，我就会做一个计算。
If it takes me 10 seconds to get one training example.
假如我需要10秒去得到一个训练样例，
If I wanted to get 10
如果我需要10倍多数据，
times as much data, then I need 10,000 examples.
那么我需要10000个样例。
So I do the calculation, how long
所以我做一下计算，看一下
is it gonna take to label,
加标签需要多少时间，也就是手工
to manually label 10,000 examples,
给10000个样例加标签需要多少时间。
if it takes me 10 seconds to label 1 example.
假如给一个样例加标签需要10秒。
So when you do this calculation,
所以当你计算的时候，
often I've seen many you
我经常看到许多人
would be surprised, you know,
会很吃惊，时间多么短，
how little, or sometimes a
有时只是
few days at work, sometimes a
几天的工作，
small number of days of work,
有时只是少数的几天，
well I've seen many teams be very
我已经看过许多小组
surprised that sometimes how
感到很吃惊，
little work it could be,
获得更多的数据
to just get a lot more
需要的工作是多么少，
data, and let that be
把这个
a way to give your learning
做为大力提高
app to give you a huge boost
提高你机器学习应用
in performance, and necessarily, you
性能的方法，你知道这是必然的，
know, sometimes when you've just
有时当你实际
managed to do this, you
做到这一点了，
will be a hero and whatever product
你将是一个英雄，无论是
development, whatever team you're working
什么产品开发，
on, because this can
无论你在哪个小组工作，
be a great way to get much better performance.
因为这是一个非常好提高性能的方法。
Third and finally, one sometimes
第三个也是最后一个，
good way to get a
有时一个获得更多
lot of data is to use
数据的方法
what's now called crowd sourcing.
叫做众包。
So today, there are a
现在，有一些
few websites or a few
网站，或者是一些服务，
services that allow you
允许你
to hire people on
在网上雇一些人，
the web to, you know, fairly
你知道的，可以非常便宜的
inexpensively label large training sets for you.
帮你标记大量的训练集。
So this idea of crowd
所以众包的思想，
sourcing, or crowd sourced
或者叫众包
data labeling, is something
标记数据，
that has, is obviously, like
很明显有点像
an entire academic literature,
一个完整的学术文化，
has some of it's own complications and
有它自己的诸多问题，
so on, pertaining to labeler reliability.
它很依赖于加标记的人的可靠性。
Maybe, you know, hundreds of thousands
可能，你知道，世界上
of labelers, around the
有成千上万的
world, working fairly inexpensively to
标记人员在廉价地工作，
help label data for you,
帮你给数据加标签，
and that I've just had mentioned,
正如我刚才所说的，
there's this one alternative as well.
这也是一个可供选择的办法。
And probably Amazon Mechanical Turk
亚马逊土耳其机器人
systems is probably the most
系统可能是当前
popular crowd sourcing option right now.
最流行的众包选择。
This is often quite a
假如你想
bit of work to
得到高质量的标签，
get to work, if you want
这个通常是
to get very high quality labels,
很容易完成的工作，
but is sometimes an
但是这有时也是一个
option worth considering as well.
很值得考虑的选择。
If you want to try to
如果你想
hire many people, fairly inexpensively
在网上花费不多
on the web, our labels launch miles of data for you.
雇佣很多人，我们的标记可以做为数据投放到市场。
So this video, we
所以，这一个视频，
talked about the idea of
我们讨论了
artificial data synthesis of
利用人工数据合成的方法
either creating new data
从头开始
from scratch, looking, using
生成新的数据，察看夯基金
the ramming funds as an example,
并以它为例，
or by amplifying an
或者是使用
existing training set, by taking
现有的训练集，引入
existing label examples and
introducing distortions to it,
一些失真，以生成另外
to sort of create extra label examples.
以生成额外的标签样例。
And finally, one thing that
最后一件
I hope you remember from this
我希望你通过这个视频
video this idea of if
能记住的事情就是
you are facing a machine learning
假如你正面对
problem, it is often worth doing two things.
一个机器学习问题，有两件事情是值得做的。
One just a sanity check,
一个就是通过学习曲线做一个完整的检查，
with learning curves, that having more data would help.
有更多的数据将会更有力。
And second, assuming that that's the case,
第二个就是，假如情况是这样，
I will often seat down and
我通常会坐下来，
ask yourself seriously: what would
认真的问自己，
it take to get ten times as
获取到十倍于
much creative data as you
当前的创造
currently have, and not always,
出来的数据，不是经常，
but sometimes, you may be
但是有时，你会
surprised by how easy that
吃惊的发现，
turns out to be, maybe
事实上这很简单，可能需要几天，
a few days, a few weeks at
可能是几个周的工作，
work, and that can be
并且这是一个很好的方法，
a great way to give your learning algorithm a huge boost in performance
它可以大幅提高你的机器学习方法的性能。